<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://argh.technology/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Argh.technology</title><link>http://argh.technology/</link><description>Half (or less) formed thoughts</description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 17:36:31 +0100</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2023-05-26-more-pictures/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2023-05-26-more-pictures/</link><title>More Pictures</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have finally gotten round to processing pictures I shot at a few gigs last month. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-04-07-Toxik_Ephex%2BThe_Eddies%2BMark_Ayling/gallery.html'&gt;Toxik Ephex + The Eddies + Mark Ayling on 7th April&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-04-07-Toxik_Ephex%2BThe_Eddies%2BMark_Ayling/gallery.html'&gt;&lt;img src="https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-04-07-Toxik_Ephex%2BThe_Eddies%2BMark_Ayling/DSC05778.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-08-15-8bit_psycho%2BCuttin_a_rug%2BNumbskulls/gallery.html'&gt;Numbskulls + Cuttin a Rug + 8bit Psych on 15th April&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-08-15-8bit_psycho%2BCuttin_a_rug%2BNumbskulls/gallery.html'&gt;&lt;img src="https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-08-15-8bit_psycho%2BCuttin_a_rug%2BNumbskulls/DSC06279.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-04-28%20Atomic%20Mother%20%2B%20Blackfyre%20Rising%20%2B%20History%20of%20Concrete/gallery.html'&gt;Atomic Mother + Blackfyre Rising + History of Concrete on 28th April&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-04-28%20Atomic%20Mother%20%2B%20Blackfyre%20Rising%20%2B%20History%20of%20Concrete/gallery.html'&gt;&lt;img src="https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-04-28%20Atomic%20Mother%20%2B%20Blackfyre%20Rising%20%2B%20History%20of%20Concrete/DSC07470.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That has me caught up on the queue of pictures waiting to get processed - so I will have to take camera down to Krakatoa this evening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm mostly liking the A7R, but there are a couple of things I miss from the GX80. On the GX80 with manual lenses I would usually put it in aperture priority mode and let it pick shutter speed and ISO, and it did a reasonable job of those, the A7R was picking way too long a shutter speed when I did that, and I couldn't find a way to set any limits on what it should use, so have been having to do manual setting of shutter speed. I also can't seem to get a histogram in live view, only in playback once the shot is taken, with the constantly changing light of a gig that isn't much help. I need to change my thinking on framing a bit for this camera: I've now got plenty of resolution to crop in a bit when processing so should be shooting looser to give space to pick final crop when processing. Quite a few of pictures in above galleries would have been better with a bit more space - and there are a few that didn't make it into the gallery as they chopped body parts awkwardly. This is holdover from the GX80 not having enough resolution to crop much before it starts looking bad. A7R has enough resolution that cropping down to ¼ of frame is still more pixels that a 4K screen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2023-04-07-new-camera/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2023-04-07-new-camera/</link><title>New Camera</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have gotten myself a new camera. A Mk 1 A7R. It is quite a long way from actually being new: about 10 years old. So, older than my old GX80 that it is replacing. But full frame and 36 megapixels vs. 2x crop and 16 megapixels so mostly quite an upgrade. I've been lusting after one of these since they first launched and when I saw one on mpb for £230 I clicked the button (they still normally fetch around £500, this one has some issues). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took it out to a couple of gigs at Krakatoa last weekend, and have now got round to processing the &lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-04-02-first-2-gigs-with-A7R/gallery.html'&gt;pictures from that.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-04-02-first-2-gigs-with-A7R/gallery.html'&gt;&lt;img src="https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-04-02-first-2-gigs-with-A7R/DSC04583_640.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't have any native Sony lenses yet. Using the various PK and M42 manual lenses I've collected since I got the GX80 and started playing with vintage lenses. I'm considering getting the Sony 18-50 PZ to use the A7R for a walking about camera, but not sure if it would be worth it for the few occasions I might take a real camera out rather than just using my phone but don't want to take a better lens. &lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2023-02-19-Sigma-PK-70-210/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2023-02-19-Sigma-PK-70-210/</link><title>Sigma PK 70-210 f2.8</title><description>&lt;p&gt;September last year (though it doesn't feel that long ago) I got myself a new lens. Well, actually quite an old lens that was new to me. A Sigma Pentax-K mount 70-210mm f2.8. It was surprisingly cheap for an f2.8 tele-zoom: £120. I have a 135mm prime that I quite like, but often find I'm too lazy to swap to other lenses and end up with all my pictures being a bit samey. I figured having a zoom that crossed that 135mm might let me introduce a bit more variation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've now taken it out a few times and did get some pictures I'm happy with (and a lot that where the focus isn't even close). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-02-playing-with-sigma-PK70-210/gallery.html'&gt;&lt;img src="https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2023-02-playing-with-sigma-PK70-210/P1120800_1920.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of those were with adaptor that just connects the different mounts. I have now got a .72x focal reducer that will make it a bit wider and faster. On my GX80 it'll be roughly equivalent of a 100-300mm f2 on 35mm. So far I've only had a few minutes to play with it, looking forward to getting out with it to have a longer play. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This takes me up to a dozen lenses that I can use with me GX80 - and only the kit lens that came with it has autofocus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about getting a better camera. Micro 4/3 mostly haven't really moved on enough from the GX80 to be much of an upgrade. The GH6 would be a nice step up, but I don't much like the form factor. Or the price. I'm still hopeful Panasonic might make a GX camera with the sensor from the GH6, but there would probably be a fairly long wait before any would be available at a price I'd be willing to pay. Considering moving to another mount top of my list would be Fujifilm X-something or Sony A6000 series. There seems to be fewer options for adapting weird old lenses to Fujifilm X-mount than Sony E (or micro 4/3) - e.g. I couldn't find an equivalent of the Pentax-K focal reducer I just got for Fujifilm X, but there are a few options for Sony E. That has me leaning towards A6000 series - some of them are even old enough to be available at price I might be willing to pay..&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2023-01-10-ohm-bee-uns/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2023-01-10-ohm-bee-uns/</link><title>Ω 🐝 🥁</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have had vague thoughts for a while to make a thing to display random gifs, videos, or other animations as a thing to do with my various screens when they aren't needed to be displaying other things. Kind of like the old days when we used screensavers, but controlled over the network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to &lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/ohm.bee.uns'&gt;making it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted this to be a web thing so that I only need a browser on whatever displays I want to use. &lt;a href='https://nim-lang.org/'&gt;Nim&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href='https://github.com/dom96/jester'&gt;Jester&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://github.com/karaxnim/karax'&gt;Karax&lt;/a&gt; are my current favourite approach to web dev. I came across a &lt;a href='https://arhamjain.com/2021/11/22/nim-simple-chat.html'&gt;nice example&lt;/a&gt; using this stack that also introduced me to &lt;a href='https://htmx.org/'&gt;htmx&lt;/a&gt; that makes the "open a websocket and display whatever html blobs you get from it" that I wanted for the client side really easy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The code itself isn't much use without a collection of animations for it to be serving up. My collection has been built up by saving things I've come across in various places online. Most of which I don't have rights to redistribute (and even the ones that are under licenses that would allow that I haven't kept note of that). &lt;a href='https://www.beeple-crap.com/vjloops'&gt;Beeple's VJ loops&lt;/a&gt; are a good start with CC license (though I couldn't find anything saying which CC license). The collection should be in &lt;code&gt;public/img/&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;ohm.bee.uns&lt;/code&gt; checkout (or relative to working directory for executable if that is a different place). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current version just gives each client a new random animation every 60 seconds. Some way to stop that and blank all the clients is probably the next thing I'll add. After that I'd like to add some administration to add tags to animations in the collection, and then set selection of animations to limit to exclude animations that match a list of tags. Would like to be able to set config for all displays or subsets of them. I would like to try making a (crappy) video wall by sending the same html blob to multiple clients but setting viewport so they only display a part of it. Should really move styling to a CSS file rather than a load of &lt;code&gt;style=&lt;/code&gt; all over the place. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can imagine using this (with a couple more features implemented) on displays for a confrence. During talks displays could be set to stream of presenter or screenshare (or output of vision mixer to have someone switching between those or PiP of both) and between talks could be schedule info and/or random animations. &lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2022-10-23-hackdeenbot-v2/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2022-10-23-hackdeenbot-v2/</link><title>hackerdeenbot v2</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In the dim and distant past I made an &lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/spacebot'&gt;IRC bot&lt;/a&gt; for what was then hackerdeen hackspace. It was written in clojure and had become more hassle than it worth to keep running. This was a combination of friction from JVM (it'll eat &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the memory if you're not careful, has it's own SSL cert handling etc.) and my code not being very good at handling disconnects so regularly needing to be manually restarted. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to move to something that would have a more complete IRC client (handling authentication, reconnects etc.) and giving me an interface to send messages from external things happening (e.g. space is opened/closed) and respond to commands. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Options I know of for this are &lt;a href='https://tools.suckless.org/ii/'&gt;suckless ii&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://github.com/irccloud/irccat'&gt;irccat&lt;/a&gt;. I plumped for irccat, mostly because I had used it before so already kind of knew what I was doing to configure it and the approach to commands is a bit easier there: irccat will call a command handler executable with some env variables to give context of the command trigger and that executable just needs to print to console for response where with ii you'd have to parse the stream of messages for all channels watching for commands (I didn't get as far as figuring out how that would work for PRIVMSG commands) then write response to appropriate file. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn't port over all of the "features" of original hackerdeenbot - some of them connected to other systems that don't exist any more and some were silly jokes that even I think have run their course now. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/misc/blob/main/command_handler.py'&gt;commands&lt;/a&gt; I did implement:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; !gary: summon gary
 !ping: pong
 !membership: how many members have paid?
 !histogram: graph of how many members have paid
 !rules: space rules
 !rule &amp;lt;n&amp;gt;: the nth rule
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plus messages when the space is &lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/misc/blob/main/watch_status.py'&gt;opened or closed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2022-06-27-more-gig-photos/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2022-06-27-more-gig-photos/</link><title>More Gig Photos</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Since my &lt;a href='/posts-output/2022-06-13-gig-photos/'&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; I have been along to a few more heats of Krakatoa's battle of the bands. For some of them I took pictures. And I have now got round to processing those pictures. Definitely still rusty but I think getting better. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The heat numbering seems to have gotten broken: there was a heat between heats 4 and 5 in &lt;a href='https://www.57north.org/listings/2022/06'&gt;the listings&lt;/a&gt; so I'm just going to go for dates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-06-24-Eruption-heat/gallery.html'&gt;24th June&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-06-24-Eruption-heat/gallery.html'&gt;&lt;img src="https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-06-24-Eruption-heat/P1080601.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-06-25-Eruption-heat/gallery.html'&gt;25th June&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-06-25-Eruption-heat/gallery.html'&gt;&lt;img src="https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-06-25-Eruption-heat/P1080918.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-07-02_Eruption_Heat_5/gallery.html'&gt;2nd July&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-07-02_Eruption_Heat_5/gallery.html'&gt;&lt;img src="https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-07-02_Eruption_Heat_5/P1090292.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think I need to figure something else out as an index for galleries. I like my &lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/gallerygen'&gt;simple static gallery generator&lt;/a&gt; and then chucking the files into whatever web hosting I feel like but could do with a single jumping off point to link to individual galleries. &lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2022-06-13-gig-photos/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2022-06-13-gig-photos/</link><title>Gig Photos</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Last Friday was the first round of the local battle of the bands at Krakatoa. I went along (and brought camera with me). It was nice to see things getting back to something resembling "normal".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am definitely out of practice taking pictures. Most were really poorly framed, and I really should have mixed up the lens used to get some variation - I took 4 lenses with me but didn't bother actually changing off the 50mm f1.1 that was on the camera when I started. This was the first time I'd taken that lens to a gig, I was impressed with how much light it was pulling in and letting me get reasonable ISO and shutter speeds despite the low light. I think could have actually got better results stopping it down a bit to get sharper images. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Got &lt;a href='https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-06-10_Eruption_Heat_1/gallery.html'&gt;a few pictures that were OK&lt;/a&gt; and one that I'd go as far as calling good:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://f002.backblazeb2.com/file/ormiret-pub/2022-06-10_Eruption_Heat_1/P1080444.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2021-12-27-age/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2021-12-27-age/</link><title>Alternative years</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week someone gave me their age using a numeric base larger than 10 to reduce the number of years. This got me thinking about other ways to mess with ages. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Years are different on other planets and we probably know of enough exoplanets now to give pretty good translation to any age you want... &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id="ROOT"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="/img/planets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="how"&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got a CSV of exoplanet data from &lt;a href='https://exoplanetarchive.ipac.caltech.edu/index.html'&gt;NASA Exoplanet Archive&lt;/a&gt;, did some faffing in python REPL to make a &lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/misc/blob/main/planets/planets.json'&gt;json file&lt;/a&gt; from that with just name and period, then wrote &lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/misc/blob/main/planets/planets.nim'&gt;some nim&lt;/a&gt; to find the best of those planets for the desired age.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2021-12-27-clock/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2021-12-27-clock/</link><title>Progress Bar Clock</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I've long had an idea to make a clock out of progress bars. I needed to figure out how to handle time based events in karax/nim/js for a bigger project so figured this was a good little project to poke at that some. &lt;div id="ROOT"&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="/img/prog.css"&gt; &lt;script type="text/javascript" src="/img/prog.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source is &lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/misc/blob/main/progress_clock/prog.nim'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2020-08-15-building-houses/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2020-08-15-building-houses/</link><title>Building Houses In Gardens</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have a garden that I don't use. It's about the same size as the footprint of my flat. I think it would be a much better use of the space to put another house on it. I'm unlikely to ever actually do that because planning application to do it would cost money and be a lot of hassle. I don't know the odds of actually getting the planning permission but "low" is likely a good first approximation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href='https://www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/birthsdeathsandmarriages/families/bulletins/familiesandhouseholds/2018#:~:text=In%202018%2C%20there%20were%2027.6%20million%20households%20in%20the%20UK,10%2Dyear%20period%20from%202008.'&gt;27.6 million households&lt;/a&gt; in the UK and &lt;a href='https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/environmentalaccounts/articles/oneineightbritishhouseholdshasnogarden/2020-05-14'&gt;80% of people have access to a garden&lt;/a&gt; so I think there is decent scope for there being more than just me with a garden that would be better off as another house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If someone were to offer to do the planning application (and build) for me in exchange for a split of the sale of the new house, I'd be keen to take them up on that. (If anyone does want to make that offer please get in touch.) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think there is a workable business model in making that offer. The odds of getting planning permission for any one application might be "low" but make enough of them and some will come through. If you're making a bunch of planning applications you'll have some economies of scale. You could go nuts and automate the whole process (plonk plans for a kit home on map for the site; submit that) and just spam them at planning offices, but I think that's likely to just piss off planning officers and get them all rejected. Something with automated preparation and having a person check them over and only submit ones with best chance of getting approved is likely to work better. Should be able to learn (either with machines or people) what features influence the probability of getting approval. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's tens of thousands of pounds of value in each successful application so even with a "low" success rate that funds a bit of work on all the applications. Could experiment to find the point that gives best ROI to working on the applications. As you scale up there's more scope for more sophisticated automation of the preparation and ranking. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you've got planning permission it would be pretty easy to get loans to cover the cost of actually building. You could just sell the plots once they have planning permission and pocket (your split of) the value of the planning permission but I think it would work better to do the building yourself: there would be economies of scale there too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This could be bootstrapped by a person/team with some knowledge of tech&lt;a href='#fn-1' id='fnref1'&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and planning applications. I don't have the knowledge of the planning process side of it so I'm not likely to do anything with this idea. But I think it has legs, and building more houses is definitely important. If anyone does have that knowledge (or the money to hire it) I'd be keen to talk. Or if anyone wants to run with this themselves: I'd be keen to be a customer. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol class='footnotes'&gt;&lt;li id='fn-1'&gt;I'm not actually sure there is much/any new tech required here. Manually filling in details on a template planning application would probably work, depends how long that takes and the success rate of the applications.&lt;a href='#fnref1'&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2020-07-07-hp-psu/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2020-07-07-hp-psu/</link><title>HP server PSU</title><description>&lt;p&gt;The guy with the Swiss accent &lt;a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0IX3euYOb5E'&gt;covered&lt;/a&gt; using server PSUs as a cheap 12V power supply. I had seen other computer PSUs converted to use outside of the computers they were intended for but this one tempted me to go for it since it has all it's power as one 12V output and it can drive 62.5A on that output (there are also 1200W models, but 750W seemed like enough for me). And for less than £15. So I got three.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They've got a few part/model numbers: Regulatory Model No. HSTNS-PL18, Generic Part No. 506821-001, Part No. 506822-001 and Spare Part No. 511778-001.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First thing I did was power one up and poke at it with a meter. That confirmed that the always on 12V line was where I was expecting it, +12V on pin 37 and GND on pin 30. This always on connection is good for 30W. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I then soldered a switch between pins 33 and 36. Closing that switch powered on the main 12V output. And some more poking with a meter and some loads confirmed that pin 34 gave an on/off status of a little over 3V and pin 34 gave a voltage that varied with load. This looked about right for the 20A per V I was expecting. That confirmed all the details of the pinout that I cared about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/img/hp-psu/pinout.png" alt="pinout" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now for some unnecessary complications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/img/hp-psu/control.png" alt="circuit" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then had a bit of a detour to hunt for level shifters that are definitely around here somewhere to control a 5V relay board from the ESP, eventually gave up on finding them and switched out the 5V relay board to a pi hat one that would work from 3.3V, and then a lot of cursing at the ESP failing to boot because I'd used a pin it cares about at boot for the relay control line and it had a pull down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But eventually got everything hooked up and working.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/img/hp-psu/final.jpg" alt="photo" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I put together a quick &lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/micropython/blob/master/hp_psu.py'&gt;micropython script&lt;/a&gt; to switch it on/off when the button is pressed and report the load. With webrepl I can get that over the network:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Load:  6  -&amp;gt;  0.386722  Amps
Load:  6  -&amp;gt;  0.386722  Amps
Touch
Load:  29  -&amp;gt;  1.86916  Amps 
Load:  30  -&amp;gt;  1.93361  Amps 
Load:  29  -&amp;gt;  1.86916  Amps 
Load:  30  -&amp;gt;  1.93361  Amps 
Touch 
Load:  10  -&amp;gt;  0.644537  Amps 
Load:  9  -&amp;gt;  0.580084  Amps
Load:  9  -&amp;gt;  0.580084  Amps
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things I want to add:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Switch on/off over the network. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feed load info into something to store/graph/... it. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some kind of case. Could do with boxing it up a bit to have something to mount the control electronics and output connectors to. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fuses for the outputs. My 12V wiring did start a little fire in the Scottish consulate tent at one of the events, I'd rather not repeat that. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Decent gauge wire. I've been  using speaker wire for testing so far. It definitely can't handle 62.5A.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2020-06-10-pstree/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2020-06-10-pstree/</link><title>The pstree options I want</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;code&gt;pstree&lt;/code&gt; every so often to investigate how something was called or what something has spawned. I almost always want the same behaviour: show me parents and children of this process, with PIDs and usernames. To get that I should use &lt;code&gt;pstree -sup &amp;lt;PID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now I should know where to look when I can't remember what the options I want are.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2018-04-02-network-effect/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2018-04-02-network-effect/</link><title>Network effect</title><description>&lt;p&gt;As Warren Ellis &lt;a href='http://morning.computer/2018/04/network-effects/'&gt;recently mentioned&lt;/a&gt;: once upon a time if your kink was one in a million you needed to be in a fairly big city to find a single digit number of people who might be on the same page. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finding them was a non-trivial exercise. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those days are past (but recent enough that I can remember them). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The internet now connects &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Internet_usage'&gt;3.something billion people&lt;/a&gt;. A one in a million kink lumps you in with a few thousand people. And they're only a Google search away. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You need to be a couple orders of magnitude further off the beaten track if you want to stand out these days.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2018-01-02-save-battery-life/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2018-01-02-save-battery-life/</link><title>Save chrome eating battery life</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I seem to collect chrome tabs. I usually have a few dozen open, often many more if I haven't cleaned them out for a while. Once upon a time reboots would clear them out but these days I reopen the previous session when I boot so tabs don't go away unless I actually tell them to. Lots of them do stuff in the background so chrome ends up using a decent chunk of CPU time. It is almost always at the top of the list in powertop. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the time I don't care about this. If my computer is plugged in then it's fine. When I'm running on battery though I care a lot more. Then when I'm doing something that I don't need the web I put chrome to sleep with &lt;code&gt;killall -STOP chrome&lt;/code&gt; and then when I want it back: &lt;code&gt;killall -CONT chrome&lt;/code&gt;. Bind those two commands to keys and I can stop and start chrome as needed, and when I don't need it it doesn't get to eat my precious battery life. &lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2017-10-19-new-camera/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2017-10-19-new-camera/</link><title>I want a new camera</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I think it's about time I got a new camera. I've thought this for a while, but keep baulking at the price of getting something that would be a decent improvement over what I currently have. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="what&amp;#95;i&amp;#95;have"&gt;What I have&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a Sony A55 at the moment. The internet tells me it was released in 2010, and I think I got mine between Christmas and New Year that year. On the lens side I've a Sigma 18-250 super zoom and a 50mm prime that cover most of what I do and I still have the 18-70 kit zoom from my A200 that I sometimes use as I have close focus filters that fit it and let it get really up close to stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="what&amp;#95;i&amp;#95;want"&gt;What I want&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'd like better performance - noise levels at higher ISOs look much better on more modern cameras, higher res video and not overheating when shooting video would be nice and, though 16 megapixels is usually plenty for what I do more would allow a bit more cropping. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, the overriding consideration for me getting a new camera is to get something smaller. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My current setup is big enough and heavy enough that I mostly leave it at home - I want something small enough that it would live in my laptop bag (since that comes most places with me), and not be something that I have to think about if it comes or not when I'm travelling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I definitely want a viewfinder on a camera. I much prefer that to only having a screen - I think it helps to have the picture you're taking be all that you see when composing it. This apparently makes me a bit weird as it seems to be only a small subset of cameras that still have viewfinders. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="what&amp;#95;i'm&amp;#95;considering"&gt;What I'm considering&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="micro&amp;#95;4/3"&gt;Micro 4/3&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the most part the micro 4/3 bodies are a lot smaller than my current camera. The lenses are definitely smaller from targeting the smaller sensor - which has the nice effect of them also being quite a bit cheaper than equivalents for APS-C or 35mm. I really like the Panasonic rangefinder style GX cameras. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="canon&amp;#95;eos&amp;#95;m5"&gt;Canon EOS M5&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;APS-C 24 megapixel sensor in quite a compact body. But quite expensive, doesn't do 4K and a disappointing and expensive selection of native lenses. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="nikon&amp;#95;1&amp;#95;v3"&gt;Nikon 1 V3&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seems to be quite expensive for the specs. Again the native lenses have a disappointing selection and look expensive. And they're a pain to find as search results are swamped by "normal" Nikon lenses - "1" is a stupid name for a lens type.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="sony&amp;#95;mirrorless"&gt;Sony mirrorless&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe switch over to Sony E-mount? A6000 looks like it would be a decent step up from the A55. There's a decent amount of E-mount lenses available (though a bit more expensive than micro 4/3) and adaptors to let you use just about anything else. A bit higher res than the best of the micro 4/3 cameras. I was pretty tempted by the A6500 when it came out, but I don't think I want to spend that much and the jelly from the rolling shutter seems particularly bad with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="a&amp;#95;compact&amp;#95;camera"&gt;A compact camera&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I really want to go all out on small: get something like a Sony Rx100 or Panasonic LX100. These are small enough to put in a pocket or clip onto my belt so could definitely come everywhere with me. I'm not really sold on giving up on interchangeable lenses though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="lenses"&gt;Lenses&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think a small normal crossing zoom would be the best bet for usually living on the camera lens. That should give a nice small package for always carrying around and still be reasonably flexible. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've seen a few reviews of the  Olympus 40-150 that say it's quite good and very good for the price: from ~£50 on eBay. If I get a micro 4/3 camera I'll probably get one of these to have something for the longer end. Might not get that right away. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Panasonic 12-35 f2.8, or Olympus 12-40 f2.8  "premium"/"professional" zooms look really nice, but they start at ~£500 on eBay so would eat pretty much all of my budget without getting a camera to put them on. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Micro 4/3 or Sony E-mount have a pretty small flange to sensor distance and with the sensors being quite small (especially micro 4/3) you can get adaptors to use most other types of lenses. There are a lot of really cheap and fast C-mount lenses out there, and some old M42 lenses look quite nice. C-mount extension tubes look fun for some macro stuff.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="speed&amp;#95;booster"&gt;Speed Booster&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metabones Speed Booster gives a 0.71x focal length multiplier (on the ultra, 0.64 on XL variants) to allow full frame lenses to be used while kind of counteracting the crop from the small sensor and making the lens about a stop faster. The metabones version is quite expensive (and not widely available - I haven't yet found any for sale in Europe), there are a couple of cheaper alternatives, but reviews I've seen have been fairly negative for them. Since, to me, the whole point of this kind of adaptor would be to use some of the nice older lenses the adaptor adding issues would kind of spoil that. If I can live with distortion and vignetting C-mount lenses at about equivalent speeds are a couple of orders of magnitude cheaper. Some nice older lenses on a Speed Booster is fun to fantasise about but is probably still more expensive than I'm likely to spend in the near future. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Speed Booster would let me get some fast older manual primes and make them even faster. Or there are versions that support modern AF lenses but those adaptors are more expensive and the lenses tend to be lots more expensive. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="crop&amp;#95;factor"&gt;Crop factor&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was a bit worried about the crop factor taking away some of the wide end. My current widest lens is 18mm on the wide end of my kit and super zooms - adn I have often wanted something a bit wider than that. On my APS-C camera that comes in at about 29mm full frame equivalent. Need about 14mm to match that so the cheap standard zooms are about what I currently have and the premium/pro/bloody expensive standard zooms would be a bit wider. EBay has some cheap C-mount lenses out to 7mm without being listed as fisheye but they might have enough distortion that they actually would be fisheye in my book. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="conclusion?"&gt;Conclusion?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm still havering. I have bid on a couple of GX7s on eBay but other people seem to think they're worth more than I do, so haven't won them. I'm really surprised how much they go for, only £50-100 less than a GX80 (and second hand GX80s are surprising close to new ones - the higher end of the range are listing them above the new price on Amazon). I think the improved detail from the GX80 not having the low-pass filter makes it worth the extra over the GX7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, I'm currently leaning towards a Panasonic GX80 with the kit zoom and a couple of C-mount manual primes. Can maybe upgrade to native, or M42 primes later. I think I'll spend a while watching them on eBay but it is very tempting to push the button on Amazon to get one tomorrow...&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2017-02-26-VNC-extra-monitors/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2017-02-26-VNC-extra-monitors/</link><title>VNC extra monitors</title><description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of times in the past I've thought about using other computers/tablets as additional displays for my main computer. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This time I actually found a &lt;a href='https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=191555'&gt;way to do it&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;xrandr&lt;/code&gt; can be used to create a new monitor without the need for an actual monitor, I used the &lt;code&gt;VIRTUAL1&lt;/code&gt; output and was pleased to see a &lt;code&gt;VIRTUAL2&lt;/code&gt; pop into existence when I did. Then &lt;code&gt;x11vnc&lt;/code&gt; with an appropriate &lt;code&gt;-clip&lt;/code&gt; can make a VNC server for that bit of the virtual desktop. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tried both a spare laptop and my tablet as extra displays and it seems to work well with either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tablet as extra screen will be quite nice when I'm travelling. &lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2017-02-06-this-too-shall-pass/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2017-02-06-this-too-shall-pass/</link><title>This Too Shall Pass</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I love this adage. Having read &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_too_shall_pass'&gt;the Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; on it (you have to like any sentence that has its own Wikipedia article) I seem to be in good company; there's wise men, various royals and Abe Lincoln. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my plans for if/when I have stupid amounts of money to throw at frivolous projects: write this somewhere that the passing will take a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can probably afford to get it carved in a lump of granite now. Wandering round a graveyard gives you an idea of how long that'll take to pass. I put it at a couple of centuries (if you can stop future people finding a better use for the chunk of granite for that long). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of making a standing stones version of the phrase. Stone henge, and &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_stone_circles'&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ring_of_Brodgar'&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/88/Tyrebagger_Stone_Circle_-_geograph.org.uk_-_257895.jpg'&gt;stone&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easter_Aquhorthies_stone_circle'&gt;circles&lt;/a&gt;, suggest that these can last a few millenia. Though we don't really know how many didn't survive...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next step up would be to reshape a mountain to spell it out. &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Rushmore'&gt;Mt Rushmore&lt;/a&gt; style. A &lt;a href='https://atkinsbookshelf.wordpress.com/tag/what-would-it-cost-to-build-mount-rushmore-now/'&gt;quick Google&lt;/a&gt; puts the cost of that on the order of $10 billion. A bit out of my price range at the moment. But about pocket change for a decent sized government. Anybody contemplating a &lt;a href='https://www.theguardian.com/politics/reality-check-with-polly-curtis/2011/sep/12/reality-check-banking-bailout'&gt;bank bailout&lt;/a&gt; or a couple of &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queen_Elizabeth-class_aircraft_carrier'&gt;aircraft carriers&lt;/a&gt;: how about carving a mountain to say "This too shall pass" instead? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Properly into mad billionaire territory (I'm looking at you Elon Musk) we could write it on the moon. I could take a swing at figuring out what that would take and how long it would last but this seems like the kind of problem that can be outsourced to &lt;a href='https://what-if.xkcd.com/'&gt;xkcd/what if&lt;/a&gt;. I have submitted it so I guess we'll see if Randall's productivity is sufficiently superior to mine that he gets to a random submission before I get round to looking into something I've actually wondered about.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2016-09-03-photography/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2016-09-03-photography/</link><title>Photography</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I was thinking today that I haven't been doing much photography lately. Given I had a bit of free time the obvious thing to do would have been to get out my camera and take some pictures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't like to do the obvious thing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead I started thinking about a process to get me taking more pictures. I decided I should set myself a schedule that I can keep to of shooting something. I've previously tried a daily schedule (with a group all shooting on the same theme each day) but within a week I got distracted by other things and then forgot about it. This time I think I'll try weekly. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With that decided I needed an idea of some subject matter. For the few days I stuck to the daily shooting I quite liked getting a theme and having to find something to fit it.  I tended to interpret the theme quite loosely, but it was a good starting point. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, rather than actually picking up a camera this afternoon I have assembled a &lt;a href='https://github.com/ormiret/photo-themes'&gt;list of themes&lt;/a&gt; and put together &lt;a href='http://theme.bodaegl.com'&gt;a website&lt;/a&gt; to pick one from the list. &lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2016-08-19-replacing-IR-remote/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2016-08-19-replacing-IR-remote/</link><title>Replacing IR remote</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I've picked up a few LED floodlights that can do various colours (and some effects) controlled by IR remotes. They have their uses as they are - but I want to replace the IR remotes with something connected to a computer so I can have random programs control them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="getting&amp;#95;ir&amp;#95;codes"&gt;Getting IR codes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first thing I wanted to do was record the IR codes that the remote was sending.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href='http://alexba.in/blog/2013/01/06/setting-up-lirc-on-the-raspberrypi/'&gt;some stuff&lt;/a&gt; on using &lt;a href='http://lirc.org'&gt;lirc&lt;/a&gt; on a pi, so cut one of the IR receivers off a light and hooked it up to a pi and recorded the codes from the remote. That gave &lt;a href='/code/ir-control/lircd.conf'&gt;a lirc config file&lt;/a&gt; with the codes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used keysims &lt;code&gt;KEY&amp;#95;A&lt;/code&gt; through &lt;code&gt;KEY&amp;#95;X&lt;/code&gt; for the buttons on the remote starting at the top left going across the top row, then down to the next. So &lt;code&gt;KEY&amp;#95;C&lt;/code&gt; is off, &lt;code&gt;KEY&amp;#95;D&lt;/code&gt; is on, down to &lt;code&gt;KEY&amp;#95;X&lt;/code&gt; in the bottom right for smooth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="sending&amp;#95;ir&amp;#95;codes"&gt;Sending IR codes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I started messing with this I thought I could use lirc's ability to send codes by wiring the output pin from the pi to the signal line going into the light and all would be good. I tried it and it didn't work. I thought the issue might be that the two had a different ground so the signal wasn't at the right level. I tried solving that by connecting the light and pi's grounds to each other. That switched the pi off. Luckilly it came back on, apparently none the worse for wear, once I disconnected them again. I guess they were at different levels, by enough to upset the pi's power stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided I needed some output isolation. I was sure I had some optocouplers around somewhere, but couldn't find them, so I ordered some more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While waiting for them to turn up I had a look at &lt;a href='https://arduino-info.wikispaces.com/file/view/IR-Receiver-AX-1838HS.pdf/264668680/IR-Receiver-AX-1838HS.pdf'&gt;the datasheet for the IR receiver&lt;/a&gt; and discovered that it did more than just pass the IR signal to it's output. Turns out IR remotes have a carrier (38kHz for this one) that they send, or don't, for periods of time to send things. The receiver gives a constant low when it sees the carrier and a constant high the rest of the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since lirc was set up to be sending the carrier via an IR LED the signal it was outputting wouldn't match what the light was expecting to get from the receiver module.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I considered changing lirc's output, or building a circuit to do the transform the receiver module was doing (a low pass filter and an inverter? would a cap and a transistor be enough?), but opted for swapping the pi out for an arduino to generate the right waveform since I know what I'm doing there a lot better than getting into the lirc code or doing anything analogue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just needed to figure out what the right waveform was from the &lt;a href='/code/ir-control/lircd.conf'&gt;lirc config file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I read a bit about how IR command frames work (on sites that I can't find now...). Short version is that there are a few encoding schemes the &lt;code&gt;SPACE&amp;#95;ENC&lt;/code&gt; on the &lt;code&gt;flags&lt;/code&gt; line tells us we need pulse space encoding: the length of the gap between pulses determines if it's a 1 or a 0. The timing for each of those is on the &lt;code&gt;one&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;zero&lt;/code&gt; lines; first number gives the length of the pulse, second one the length of the space before the next bit (both in microseconds). We also have a header (or in some descriptions: preamble) of one longer than normal pulse followed by a longer than normal space. Timings for those are on the &lt;code&gt;header&lt;/code&gt; line. After the header will come the 16 &lt;code&gt;pre&amp;#95;data&amp;#95;bits&lt;/code&gt;, which &lt;code&gt;pre&amp;#95;data&lt;/code&gt; line says should be &lt;code&gt;0xF7&lt;/code&gt;. Then the 16 actual data bits - which will vary depending on which of the codes we want to send. The frame then concludes with a trailing pulse (timing from &lt;code&gt;ptrail&lt;/code&gt;) and then a minimum period before the next code should be sent (&lt;code&gt;gap&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I couldn't find anything to say what the bit ordering should be. I decided I'd try "most significant bit first" first, then "least significant bit first", then the variation on byte vs bit ordering till I got an ordering that worked (or ran out of ways to reorder them and would have to go looking for something else that might be wrong). As it turned out "most significant bit first" was actually right, so didn't need to try any of the others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This figuring out had taken long enough that the optocouplers I ordered had turned up, so I decided to try doing things properly and isolate the light from the arduino. If figured I could also use this to invert the signal from the arduino so I can write the code with the output normally being low and going high for pulses. That's the way round I think of as normal so it reduces the chance of me getting bugs from getting it the wrong way round somewhere. I hooked up the optocoupler like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/img/ir-control/circuit.png" alt="circuit" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current limiting resistor between the arduino and the optocoupler is something about 220Ω, and the pull up on the light side is about 10kΩ so we don't get very much current there. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then I just needed &lt;a href='/code/ir-control/ir_command.ino'&gt;a sketch to send commands&lt;/a&gt;. This is very rough still; the command it sends is hard coded and it just loops sending it over and over. But it does work - I can switch a light on and off with it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id="next&amp;#95;steps"&gt;Next steps&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need to update the arduino sketch to allow the commands to be sent in (probably over serial). Then add support for more lights. Then I need to figure out something to actually do with a few computer controlled RGB floodlights...&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2016-08-13-new-site/</guid><link>http://argh.technology/posts-output/2016-08-13-new-site/</link><title>New site</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided to move to a new site and a new system for blogging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is being generated with &lt;a href='http://cryogenweb.org'&gt;cryogen&lt;/a&gt; to make the server side really simple and save me having to worry about code there breaking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing things for this is a lot closer to my normal work flow (I write something in emacs and then run some commands to make it appear here) so hopefully I'll actually put more on here than I have on previous attempts at blogging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It looks like it won't be a huge amount of work to pull the content from my old site into this - I'll put that on the TODO list and might get to it some time before the heat death of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I must always remember: no one cares about this blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>